字幕组
ZiMuZu.tv
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on "The Flash"...
如果我们需要阻止萨维塔
If the answers that we need
和拯救你的答案存在于未来
to stop Savitar and save you are in the future,
那我就需要去那里
then that's where I need to go.
你是来自她死之前的  对吗
You're from before she dies, aren't you?
你把萨维塔困在了神速力中
You trapped Savitar in the Speed Force.
告诉我你是怎么办到的
Just tell me how you did it.
有人帮我  她叫特蕾西·布兰德
I had help. Her name's Tracy Brown.
她为我创造了这个神速力陷阱
She made the Speed Force trap for me.
你是在说  我那个关于神速力的猜想
You're telling me my ideas about the Speed Force--
-是对的  -在未来
- I'm right? - In the future.
我们需要你现在造出陷阱
We need you to build this trap now.
她在追杀特蕾西
She was after Tracy.
这说明她在为萨维塔办事
That means she's working with Savitar.
你跟塞西尔聊了吗
So you talked to Cecile?
全告诉她了  告诉她我爱她
Told her everything. Told her I love her.
我告诉她你就是闪电侠
I told her that you're The Flash.
我从一开始就是这么告诉你的
Like I told you from the beginning...
我就是未来的闪电侠
I am the future Flash.
就像是照镜子一样
It's like looking in a mirror.
也不完全一样
Well... not quite.
没有了盔甲你也不是很吓人
You're not so scary without your armor.
我能说什么
What can I say?
红色战衣不合身了
I outgrew red.
我知道你现在是什么
I know what you are.
你是时间残余
You're a time remnant.
时间副本
A temporal duplicate.
是你穿越回去跟过去的你
Created when you run back in time
见面时产生的
and meet yourself.
去年你为了打败极速创造了一个时间残余
You brought a remnant to life last year to defeat Zoom.
你的副本为拯救多元宇宙而死
Your duplicate died, saving the multiverse,
而你继续幸福地生活着
and you continued your happy little life.
本来一切都相安无事
And it would've stayed that way,
可你却偏要去扮演上帝
but then you decided to play God.
你创造了闪点  改变了一切
You created Flashpoint and changed everything.
我是去了未来
I went to the future.
未来的我跟我说
My future self told me that
他创造了时间残余来阻止你
he created time remnants to stop you.
但你把他们都杀了
But you slaughtered them all.
除了一个
All but one.
我
Me.
我活下来了
I lived.
但我活下来后发生了一件有意思的事
But a funny thing happened when I did.
你  乔
You. Joe.
沃利  西斯科
Wally, Cisco.
因为我不是真正的巴里·艾伦
You all shunned me because I wasn't
你们都躲着我
the true Barry Allen.
我只是个时间偏差
I was an aberration.
可有可无的英雄
A disposable hero.
未来的你没跟你说这个  对吧
Future you failed to mention that, didn't he?
你怎么会变成萨维塔呢
How did you become Savitar?
我很病态
I was broken
很孤独
and alone.
我想要结束这种痛苦
I wanted the pain to end.
那时我才悟出真理  巴里
And that's when I realized the truth, Barry.
上帝不会有痛苦
God feels no pain.
我要做的就是成为上帝
All I had to do was become one.
而我只需要再做两件事
And I only need two more things:
一是让爱瑞丝死
for Iris to die
你就会陷入无尽的黑暗中
so that you are driven so far into the dark
我就可以重生了
that I can be born.
另一件是什么
And the other?
鉴于听到这话的人会觉得很讽刺
It may sound ironic given who I'm talking to,
所以我就不说了
but I'll keep that one to myself.
如果我自杀了会怎么样
What happens if I kill myself?
如果我死了  你就决不会出现
If I die, then you'll never be created.
因果关系很微妙
Cause and effect's a tricky thing.
在艾迪身上效果就不太好吧
Didn't work so well for Eddie, did it?
他朝自己胸口开了一枪
Shot himself in the chest--
斯旺还在四处穿越
Thawne's still kicking around.
这就是时间旅行的问题  巴里
See, that's the thing about time travel, Barry.
做的越多  限制你的规则就越少
The more you do it, the less the rules apply to you.
但我们现在这样对话
But us having this conversation now--
就是在改变未来
we're changing the future.
是吗
Are we?
我就快统治一切
My ascendancy is nearing.
等我掌控了所有时间
When I have control of all of time,
被抛弃  被遗忘的人将会是你
it will be you who is abandoned and forgotten.
你会死在这里
You're gonna die right here!
我忘了告诉你
I forgot to tell you--
我的战衣比你的厉害多了
my suit's cooler than yours.
闪电侠
第三季
第二十一集
不可能啊
It's impossible.
我不明白  萨维塔怎么会是你
I don't understand. How could Savitar be you?
他不是我  不完全是
He's not me. Not really.
他集合了你最坏的一面
He's all the worst parts of you.
就像《星际迷航》里
It's like in "Star Trek"
传输机把柯克分裂成了好柯克和坏柯克
when the transporter splits Kirk into good Kirk and bad Kirk.
请告诉我你的地球上至少有《星际迷航》
Please tell me you at least have "Star Trek" on your Earth.
-《重返地球》  -我讨厌衍生剧
- "Voyager." - I hate spinoffs.
《星际迷航》的衍生剧
难怪凯特琳愿意跟随他
That explains why Caitlin was willing to follow him.
她相信的是他那张脸
He has a face that she trusts.
只是一半
Half of one anyway.
所以传奇在乘波号发现老年的你
So when the Legends found that message in the Waverider
留下那条"不要相信巴里·艾伦"的信息
from old you saying "Don't trust Barry Allen,"
其实说的是萨维塔版的巴里·艾伦
it was talking about Savitar Barry Allen.
疑团以最糟糕的方式
It's all coming together...
全都解开了
in the worst way.
你说是你创造了萨维塔的吗
You said you made Savitar?
怎么会
How?
看这里
Peep this.
从现在起的四年后
Four years from now,
未来的闪电侠创造了
future Flash creates...
未来的闪电侠和时间残余
一个时间残余去对抗萨维塔
a time remnant to fight Savitar.
但萨维塔却让残余活下来了
But Savitar lets that remnant live
这样它后来就能成为萨维塔
so that it can later become Savitar.
未来的闪电侠和时间残余
所以一旦萨维塔被囚禁在神速力里
So once Savitar is imprisoned in the Speed Force,
这个残余就开始发疯了
this remnant starts to go crazy.
未来的闪电侠和时间残余
然后他穿越到过去
And he goes back in time to the past
变成了萨维塔
and becomes Savitar.
未来的闪电侠和时间残余
编造了他是第一位极速者的谎言
Creating the lie that he was the first speedster,
去各个年代散播神话  招募党羽
spreading the myth and recruiting acolytes throughout the ages.
这完全说不通啊
That doesn't make any sense.
先出现谁  萨维塔还是时间残余呢
Which came first, Savitar or the time remnant?
这是个闭环  既无开始也无结束
It's a closed loop. No beginning, no end.
未来的闪电侠和时间残余
过去       现在        未来
就是一个无尽的循环
It's just one endless cycle.
和经典的"先有鸡还是先有蛋"一样吧
Classic chicken and the egg scenario, I think, eh?
时间残余
A time remnant, it's, um--
就像是你的副本吧
it's like a duplicate of you, right?
它拥有你的感受  你的记忆
So it has your feelings, your memories.
那它为什么想要伤害我们
So why would it want to hurt us?
为什么想要杀死爱瑞丝呢
Why would he want to kill Iris?
HR  特蕾西的神速力陷阱弄得怎么样了
H.R., how's Tracy coming with the Speed Force trap?
很好  进展很慢
Good, yeah, good. Slow.
让她加快速度吧
Get her to speed up, all right?
我现在就去  可以的
I'll do that now. Can do.
如果萨维塔是未来巴里的一个版本
If Savitar is a version of Barry from the future
而且记得巴里所做的一切
and he remembers everything that Barry does,
未来的闪电侠和时间残余
过去     现在    未来
那我们要如何想办法阻止他
how are we ever going to come up with a plan to stop him?
他怎么样
What was he like?
病态
Broken.
你知道
You know...
这么久以来我都认为萨维塔是个...
all this time I thought that Savitar is this...
怪物
monster.
很难想象会发生什么
It's hard to picture what might happen,
而且你是...
and it being you that...
我知道那不是你
I--I know it's not you.
我...
I'm...
他的一部分是
Part of him is.
他说就像在照镜子  而他说得对
He said it was like looking in a mirror, and he was right.
但不仅仅是他的外貌
But not just the way that he looked.
是他的...
It was...
是他的眼睛
it was his eyes.
那里边透露出的痛苦
The pain that was inside them.
我在自己身上看到过
I've seen that in myself.
当我想起我父母如何被残忍杀害时
When I think about how my parents died so violently...
有时候我想变得更残忍来报复那种残忍
Sometimes I want to repay that violence with more violence.
我想让别人
I want to make someone else
与我一样痛苦
hurt as much as I do.
但你不会这么做
But you don't ever do that.
你不是他  你是个好人
You're not him. You're a good person.
但它就在里边  你知道  在我心中
But it's in there, you know. That's in me.
那种力量  那种痛苦
That power, that pain,
那就是萨维塔诞生的原因  因为失去
that's where Savitar comes from. From loss.
因为失去你
From losing you.
你不会失去我的
You're not going to lose me.
你听到了吗
Do you hear me?
我们会阻止萨维塔的
We are going to stop Savitar.
你不是一个人  他才是
You are not alone. He is.
而且他不是神
And he is not a god.
杰伊告诉我  我们不是神
Jay told me that we're not gods.
他说错了
He was wrong.
我们可以是
We could be.
任何极速者都可以  而且不难
Any speedster, and it wouldn't take much.
当我们内心感觉到的爱被愤怒淹灭时
When the love that we feel in our hearts is drowned in anger...
当坏记忆多过好记忆时
when the bad memories outweigh the good ones.
我要变成什么才能阻止他
What am I going to have to become to stop him?
你们  时机不对吗
Hey! Oh, bad time?
没有  怎么了
No, man, what's up?
我刚想到了一个绝佳的点子
I just came up with the best idea ever.
要不然就是超级糟糕的点子
Either that or it's the worst idea ever.
-但是  -是个点子
- But... - It's an idea.
是个点子
It's an idea!
你想给我烫个发吗
You want to give me a perm?
不是给你弄头发的  钢铁木兰[美容院]
It's not for your hair, Steel Magnolia.
这是给你大脑准备的  好吗
This is for your brain, okay?
我要让你停止创造新的记忆
I want to stop you from making new memories.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
萨维塔知道我们要做的一切
Savitar knows everything we're gonna do
是因为他记得我们做过
because he remembers doing it.
他就是未来的巴里
He's a future Barry.
那如果巴里不记得我们现在要做什么呢
So what if Barry can't remember what we're doing now?
你想要乱搞他的大脑吗
You want to mess with his brain?
就一小点
Just a little bit.
是一个很小的手术
It's a minimal procedure.
他还会是那个你认识并喜爱的巴里
It'll still be the same Barry you know and love,
只不过他没法保存新的信息了
except he just won't be able to retain new information.
大脑里有两种记忆  艾伦
There's two types of memory, Allen.
短期的和长期的
Short-term and long-term.
长期记忆是你...
Long-term is where you--
好了  朱利安  不用说了
Okay, Julian, just stop.
这是我的演示  我是这里的专家
This is my presentation; I'm the expert here.
大脑在这里保存新信息
This is the part of your brain that retains new information
然后再将它们送去皮层永久存储
before sending it to the cortex to be stored forever.
所以如果我们用
So what if we block that chain
磁性干扰阻断这个链条呢
with a magnetic disruption?
这样萨维塔就无法记得
So Savitar won't be able to remember
我们想出了什么办法来打败他
whatever strategy we come up with to defeat him.
就是说他无法再赶在我们之前了
Which means he can't be two steps ahead of us anymore.
幸运的话  我们还能先发制人
With any luck, we'll actually put him one step behind.
赞
Beautiful.
因果关系
Cause and effect.
巴里  你怎么想
Barry, what do you think?
我们就这么办
Let's do it.
等等  这里的脑部专家不是凯特琳吗
Wait, wasn't Caitlin the expert on brains around here?
她曾经是
She was.
但这次我们要在没有她的情况下完成
But this is something we'll have to do without her.
我相信你
I trust you.
你不会感觉到什么
You won't feel a thing.
好  好戏开始了
Okay, let's get this show on the road.
干扰器与你的海马体相连
The disrupter is attached to your hippocampus.
所以都准备好了
So it's ready.
好了  准备捣腾
Okay, ready for zapping.
能不说捣腾吗
Can we not call it "Zapping"?
准备激活
Ready to activate.
倒数  三
In three...
二
two...
一
one.
做个好梦  我的宝贝
Sweet dreams, my beautiful boy.
-干得漂亮  小拳王  -跑  巴里  快跑
- Way to go, slugger. - Run, Barry, run!
我一直知道你爱着爱瑞丝
I have watched you be in love with Iris...
也许我们注定会在一起
Maybe we were meant to be together.
好吧  应该可以了
Okay, that should do it.
好了
All right.
好的  你感觉怎么样
Right. How do you feel?
我感觉不错
I feel fine.
你看  他感觉不错
You see? He feels fine.
巴里
Barry...
Barry?
巴里
Barry.
巴里是谁
Who's Barry?
这可不妙
Not fine.
你们都是谁
Um, who are all of you?
发生了什么
What's going on?
你们到底是谁
Seriously, who are you guys?
好了  巴里  冷静
Okay, Barry, stay calm.
-巴里是谁  -西斯科
- Who's Barry? - Cisco!
微小的计算错误
Slight miscalculation.
我可不觉得这是微小
Slight wouldn't be a word I'd use.
我到底在哪
Where the hell am I?
这里是牙科诊所吗
Is this a dentist office?
不不  这里是尖端科研实验室
No, no. This is S.T.A.R. Labs.
实验室  实验室吗
Labs? A laboratory?
实验室  你们是什么人
St--a laboratory? What are you?
你们在拿我做实验吗
Are you guys experimenting on me?
我们没有  不过准确地说  是的
No one is ex-- well, yes, technically, yes.
但你同意了的
But--but it was consensual.
-拿我做实验  -是
- You were? - Yes.
你  为什么我什么都想不起来
You... Why can't I remember anything?
为什么我想不起来我的名字
Why can't I remember my name?
-你的名字是巴里  -我的名字不是巴里
- Your name is Barry. - My name's not Barry.
我不知道我叫什么  但我的名字是
I don't know what my name is, but my name's...
巴塞洛缪·亨利·艾伦
"Bartholomew Henry Allen."
-这什么破名字  -巴里
- That's not a good name. - Look, Barry--
你确定我不是叫巴特
Are you sure I don't go by "Bart"?
我觉得叫巴特更好
Can--"Bart" Feels more natural to me.
能叫我巴特吗
Can we go with Bart?
-巴特这名不错  -好
- Bart's kinda cool. - Okay.
-沃利  -好了
- Wally! - Okay, hey.
来  你回到椅子上
Let's just get you back in the chair.
不  不不不
No! No, no, no.
我不要坐到那椅子上
I'm not--I'm not getting in the chair.
不  我怎么知道不是你们绑架了我
No, how do I know you didn't kidnap me here
在我身上做什么奇怪的大脑实验
to do some weird brain surgery on me?
或许你们就跟那些罪犯一样
Or maybe you're like those criminals
把人骗到酒店房间
who trick people into hotel rooms
好偷他们的肾
so they can steal their kidneys.
我的肾还在吗
Do I still have my kidneys?
我们不想要你的肾
We don't want your kidneys.
巴里  看这些照片
Okay, Barry, look at these photographs.
我们是你的朋友
We're your friends.
你的家人
Your family.
我们只是想帮你  好吗
We just want to help you, okay?
这枚戒指不错
That's a nice ring.
这位幸运儿是谁
Who's the lucky guy?
是你  巴里
You are, Barry.
我知道你很害怕  好吗
Look, I know you're scared, okay?
但你可以信任我们
You can trust us.
西斯科
Cisco.
-我们谈谈  -好的
- A minute. - Yes, sir.
我马上回来  好吗
I'm gonna be right back, okay?
-沃利  陪着他  行吗  -我
- Wally, stay with him, okay? - Me?
那么  我们怎么认识的
So how do we know each other?
我是你弟弟
Oh, I'm your brother.
没有任何永久结构损伤的迹象
There is no sign of any permanent structural damage.
那他怎么什么都记不得了
Then why can't he remember anything?
朱利安
Julian?
他好像患了某种
He appears to be suffering from some sort
心因性逆向失忆症
of psychogenic retrograde amnesia.
失忆症
Amnesia.
我们是不是没有算上巴里
What if we didn't account for Barry's
由于超级速度提高了神经传导速度
increase neural velocity due to his super speed?
等等  他还知不知道自己是闪电侠
Wait, do we think he knows he's The Flash?
知道自己有超级速度吗
That he has super speed?
巴里  接住
Hey, Barry. Catch.
抱歉
Sorry.
我的天啊
Oh, my Lord.
-他状态可真差  -他真可悲
- He's, like, god-awful. - He's pathetic.
我们不能按动开关  恢复原样
Can't we flip a switch-- undo it?
在弄清这是怎么回事之前
Okay, we are not flipping any more switches
别再按什么开关了
until we figure this thing out.
是塞西尔  亲爱的
It's Cecile. Hey, babe.
很急吗
An emergency?
行  拜
All right, bye.
好吧  塞西尔让巴里去中城警局  立刻
Okay, Cecile needs Barry at CCPD, like, right now.
她说很紧急
She says it's urgent.
他这个样子不能出去
He can't possibly go out in that condition.
我和我爸带巴里去找塞西尔
Okay, um, my dad and I will take Barry to Cecile.
你和西斯科想办法找回巴里的记忆
You and Cisco figure out a way to get Barry's memory back.
尽快
And fast.
行吗
Yeah?
-行  -行
- Okay. - Okay.
你不想配合吗
You don't want to work?
那好  你滚吧
Well then, I don't need you!
我是不是可以认为
Um, am I to infer that, uh,
你遇到了一点障碍
you've hit a little speed bump
难以建造将萨维塔
in your quest to build a device
困在神速力里的设备  那个
to trap Savitar in the Speed Force? The...
加速物质微机弹
Accelerated matter microgenerator projectile.
是的  这名字真的很拗口
No, I know. It doesn't exactly roll off the tongue.
确实是  不如
No, it doesn't. How about...
我们把你这台炫酷设备叫作...
we call this fancy device of yours...
要知道  你或许不该
You know, you probably shouldn't--
-称之为  -神速力炮
- Call it the-- - Speed Force Cannon.
神速力火箭筒
Speed Force Bazooka.
神速力枪
Speed Force Gun.
-神速力火箭筒  -更好  是的
- Speed Force Bazooka. - Is better, yeah.
但如果神速力火箭筒不能马上开始运行
But if the Speed Force Bazooka doesn't start working soon,
我们就得开始称之为神速力大失败
we're gonna have to start calling it the Speed Force Epic Fail.
为什么  怎么回事
Why? What's the problem?
加速度仪
The accelerometer.
它吸取了大量气动功率  也就是说...
It sucks a hell of a lot of air watts, which--
别说科学了
Stop talking science!
你要从神速力火箭筒那里
You need to take a step back
后退一步
from the Speed Force Bazooka.
-没时间了  -总会有时间的
- There's not time. - There's always time!
因为有些时候  为了前进
Because sometimes, to move forward,
你需要退一步
you have to take a step back.
退  后
Step... back.
是吧
You see? Yes.
扭动一下
Shake a little...
活动下肩膀
Shake out those shoulders.
我感觉  我的天
I feel like-- oh, oh, my gosh.
肩膀这么僵
The tension in your shoulders--
想像让你放松的东西
Think of something that calms you.
咖啡
Coffee.
太棒了
Oh, yes.
但不是随便什么咖啡  滚烫的
But not just any coffee. Piping hot--
-对  -印尼深度烘焙豆配上
- Yep. - Indonesian dark roast with--
覆盆子和香菜
Raspberry and coriander--
我还从没遇到过另一个
I've never met another person
用大量咖啡因放松的人
who uses copious amounts of caffeine to chill out.
我也没有遇到过
I've never met another person either.
我...
I...
我放松了
I, I, I'm relaxed.
你放松了吗
Are you relaxed?
你...
You, uh...
那我就  好吧
and I'll...Okay.
我是说  好吧
I mean... okay.
早上好  大家
Good morning, people.
你好  我是巴里·艾伦
Hi. I'm Barry Allen.
你可以叫我巴特
You can call me Bart.
好  吧
O...kay.
你说有急事
So you said there was an emergency.
哪里有急事了
Where's the fire?
你这么说就有趣了
Ah, it's funny you should put it like that.
-卢西奥斯·库里奇  -谁
- Lucious Coolidge. - Who?
热侠
Heat Monger.
自从米克·罗里消失之后
The worst arsonist Central City's seen
中城最可恶的纵火犯
since Mick Rory went off the grid.
但后来闪电侠阻止了他
That is, until Flash here stopped him.
什么是闪电侠
What's Flash?
那么出什么问题了
Uh, ah, so what-- what is the problem?
汉克森法官
Judge Hankerson.
他诉讼事件表有了空档
He's got an opening in his docket,
所以他把库里奇的合理根据听证会
so he moved Coolidge's probable cause hearing
提前到了今天下午
up to this afternoon.
巴里是这案件的鉴证员
Barry was the CSI on the case.
为了能让库里奇接受审判  我需要他作证
So I need him to testify in order to hold Coolidge over for trial.
这个  不行了
Uh, yeah, no.
巴里做不了
Barry can't do that.
为什么不行
Why not?
你说他失忆了是什么意思
What do you mean he has amnesia?
巴仔  她叫什么
Bar, what's her name?
菲利希亚
Um... Felicia?
我的天
Oh, my God.
这是  这是因为
Is this--is this like a--
闪电侠的原因吗
like a Flash thing?
他在战斗时被邪恶的坏蛋用超能力偷走了
Was he battling a super villain who used his evil powers
巴里的记忆吗
to steal Barry's memory?
不是  算是我们不小心把他弄成这样的
Um, no, we sort of accidentally did this to him ourselves.
为什么
Why?
不重要  重要的是你要拖延法官
That doesn't matter. What does matter is you stalling that judge.
巴里这个状态没法出庭作证的
Barry is in no condition to testify in court.
乔  如果巴里不能作证  库里奇会无罪释放
Joe, if Barry can't testify, Coolidge walks.
就听天由命吧
And then God help us all.
好吧  我们想办法
Okay. We'll figure out something.
拜托
Please do.
很高兴认识你
It was nice meeting you.
是啊
Oh. Yeah.
我也是  巴特
You too... Bart.
我在法院有些朋友
I got some friends down at the courthouse.
我要去那里看看能不能拖一拖
I'm gonna go down there and see if we can delay
这个库里奇状况  好吧
this whole Coolidge situation, all right?
对不起
I'm sorry.
对不起什么
For what?
我不知道
I don't know.
大家似乎都很烦躁
It just seems like everybody's upset
感觉是我的错
and it feels like it's my fault.
不  完全不是
No. No, not at all.
我们只是想让你恢复正常
Look, we just want you to get back to normal.
只是如此  好吗
That's it, okay?
我会的  前提是我能记起正常是什么样
Well, I would, if I could remember what normal is.
我是说  我和你最近都在做什么
I mean, what have you and I been doing lately?
我们在计划婚礼吗
Are we planning the wedding?
比如  我们有开始发结婚请柬吗
Like, are we sending out wedding invitations
或是挑选蜜月旅行地  还有...
or picked a honeymoon destination, or...
我更喜欢温暖还是寒冷的气候
Am I a warm weather guy or a cold weather guy?
实际上  我们最近有点忙  所以...
Actually, we've been a little busy lately, so...
忙什么
With what?
不是你需要担心的事  好吗
Um, nothing that you need to worry about, okay?
好吧  还有很奇怪的是
Okay. You know what's weird?
我们刚吃过饭  但我又饿了
I know we just ate, but I'm already feeling hungry.
是吗  咱们去填饱肚子吧
Yeah, let's get some food in you.
-好的  -好
- All right. - Okay.
那句话怎么说的来着
What's that saying?
"人算不如天算"
"Man plans and God laughs?"
现在人在算
Well, men are planning.
极速之神在做什么呢
And what's the God of Speed doing?
下跪
Kneeling.
焦虑的时间结束了
Brooding time is over.
你暴露了自己
You revealed yourself.
现在怎么办
Now what?
想到怎么对付闪电侠和他的小伙伴们吗
Any idea what to do with Flash and Friends?
因为我们马上就要迎来你的大转化
Because we are getting pretty close to your big becoming,
如果我们不把他们拿下
and if we don't take them down,
你我都无法如愿以偿了
neither one of us gets what we want.
你好  有人在家吗
Hello? Anybody home?
你在做什么
What are you doing?
你是谁
Who are you?
你怎么回事
What's wrong with you?
我  是  谁
Who... am... I?
科学社团
Science club.
-青年社团  天文社团  -对
- Key Club, Astronomy Club... - Yup.
-校刊  -对
- Yearbook? - Yeah.
-还有动画社团  -对
- And anime club? - Oh, yeah.
你非常喜欢《七龙珠Z》
You loved-- loved-- "Dragon Ball Z."
我不知道这是什么
I don't know what that is.
即使我想  我也没法跟你解释这剧
Yeah, I couldn't explain that show to you even if I wanted to,
-所以  -好吧
- so... - Okay.
抱歉
Sorry.
我还真是个书呆子啊
I definitely had quite the nerd thing going on, huh?
对  有点吧
Yeah, a little bit.
你不是说我们在高中时是最好的朋友
I thought you said we were best friends in high school.
是的
Yeah, we were.
那你怎么不给我提点建议  帮帮我
Then why didn't you give me some advice, help me out?
相信我  我试过的
Oh, believe me, okay? I tried.
-是吗  你试过  -没错
- Really? You did? - Yes.
好吧  因为我有证据表明你没试过
Okay, because I have evidence that you did not.
我虽然都不记得了
Um, I don't remember any of this,
但也能看出这副打扮多丑
but even I can see how wrong that look was.
简直就是视觉恐怖袭击
This is visual terrorism.
我都无法直视了
I won't look at it anymore.
怎么了
What?
你  你和以前太不一样了  很轻松
You just... you're so different. You're so light.
什么意思
What do you mean?
我不知道  似乎你的肩上
I don't know, it's like you're not
不再有世界的重担了
carrying the weight of the world on your shoulders.
所以我之前...
So, what, I was like...
一直都很焦虑
brooding all the time before?
-有时候  -是吗
- Sometimes. - Yeah?
-是啊  -真的吗
- Yeah. - Really?
我也不知道  只是...
I don't know, it's just...
看见你笑容满面真好
it's really nice to see you smiling so much.
我...
I mean...
知道我们会
how could I not,
共度一生  我怎么会不开心
knowing I'm gonna be with you for the rest of my life?
怎么了
What?
我要去法院了
I got to get to the courthouse.
去吧
Oh, yeah, of course.
-那我走了  -好
- Yeah, I got to-- - Hey, yeah.
我...过会儿见
I'll--yeah, later. Okay.
好
Okay.
案卷号CC-15-204
Docket number CC-15-204.
证据听证会双方是中城和
Evidentiary hearing for Central City versus
被告卢西奥斯·库里奇
the defendant, Lucious Coolidge.
中城方面提请...
I see the city wishes to file...
你们来得真是时候
Cutting it real close, guys..
准备好上去作证了吗
You ready to testify?
没  我还没有
No. No, I'm not.
他准备好了  他只需要冷静一下
Yes, he is. He just needs one minute, please.
控方可以开始了
The prosecution may proceed.
来不及了  该他上了
Too late. He's up.
给  拿着这个
Here. Just take these.
我还戴眼镜
I wear glasses?
你现在需要戴  戴上就好
You will now. Just put 'em on.
你会没事的
You'll be okay.
别打湿了
Just don't get them wet.
法官阁下  我
Your Honor, I, uh--
我请求传巴里·艾伦到证人席
I call Barry Allen to the stand.
请举起你的右手
Raise your right hand, please.
你发誓说出真相  全部真相
You swear to tell the truth, the whole truth,
只说真相
and nothing but the truth?
我发誓
I do, yes.
谢谢  霍尔顿女士
Thank you. Miss Horton?
-艾伦先生  -我能坐下吗
- Mr. Allen-- - Can I sit?
请坐
Please, just...
你是一位犯罪现场鉴证员
You are a crime scene investigator
就职于中城警局  对吗
for the Central City police department, correct?
是的
这东西太酷了
Oh, this is so cool.
我很高兴你愿意作证  但是
Well, I'm so glad you enjoy testifying, but
请回答问题
please just answer the question.
好的
Of course.
是的  我是中城警局的犯罪现场鉴证员
Uh, yes, I am a CSI at the CCPD
是的  我是中城警局的
犯罪现场鉴证员
听从朱利安·艾伯特的专家指导
under the expert direction of Julian Albert.
是的  我是中城警局的犯罪现场鉴证员
听从朱利安·艾伯特的专家指导
微笑脸
Smiley face.
能把表情省了吗
Want to cut it out with the emojis?
艾伦先生
Mr. Allen,
你能否告诉我
can you tell me,
从专业角度看
in your expert opinion,
这张图片里是什么东西
what substance do you see in this photograph?
虫胶片
是紫胶片
Uh, shellac flakes.
紫胶是一种紫胶母虫分泌的树胶
Shellac is a resin secreted by female lac bugs
多见于泰国的树木上
found in large quantities of the trees in Thailand--
太快了  太...
That's too fast, that's too--
艾伦先生  你没事吧
Mr. Allen, are you all right?
没事  抱歉  我没事  我只是...
Yes, I'm sorry. I'm fine. I just, um...
这里有点热
it's getting hot in here.
紫胶片还有什么特别的地方吗
What else is unique about shellac flakes?
它是种助燃剂  所有与热侠有关的
It's the fire accelerant used in all of the arson cases
它是种助燃剂
所有与热侠有关的纵火案里都用到了
纵火案里都用到了
associated with Heat Monger.
这名字可真好笑
Such an embarrassing name.
我喜欢  我觉得可棒了
I like it. I think it's great.
你们是怎么知道
And how would you know
何时用到了紫胶片
when shellac flakes have been used?
通过计算火焰温度和灼烧图样
We calculate flame temperature and burn patterns,
有明显迹象表明紫胶燃烧
and a telltale sign is when shellac is burned
会产生高氯酸  钾
into potassium perk-er-lorate
或是高氯酸铵
or ammonium perchlorate,
那被认为是一种高温助燃火焰
which is considered a high-temperature accelerant fire.
那么
So, then...
你认为这些照片上的火
would you say the fires in these photos
能被认定为高温助燃火焰吗
would be considered high-temperature accelerant fires?
是的  因为
Uh, yes, because--
艾伦先生  你还能继续吗
Mr. Allen? Can you continue?
是的  我可以  可以继续
Yes, I can. I can continue.
没错  这些火是
The--uh, yes, the fires were
是高温助燃火
high-temperature accelerant fires,
因为火焰是
because the flames...
是  是
were, were...
明显呈黄色的
very yellow.
明显呈黄色
Very yellow?
这就是你对于助燃火给出的专业意见
And that's your expert opinion on accelerant fires?
艾伦先生
Mr. Allen?
霍尔顿女士  如果艾伦先生无法阐述
Ms. Horton, if Mr. Allen is unable to elaborate,
现在就只能驳回起诉了
I'll have no choice but to dismiss.
艾伦先生
Mr. Allen?
这个
That's--um...
驳回
Dismissed.
怎么样
How'd it go?
棒极了  纵火犯被放走了
Marvelous. They let the pyro go.
-哪里出错了吗  -没一处对的
- What went wrong? - Everything.
巴里的失忆已经开始变成麻烦了
Barry's memory loss is starting to become a problem.
当然了
It sure is.
不仅对他而言
For more than just him.
我失去速度了
I don't have my speed.
不再有了
Not anymore.
我知道原因
And I know why.
如果你想解决这个问题并帮助巴里
If you want to fix this and help Barry,
就要严格照我的话去做
you are gonna do exactly as I say.
现在因为我  热侠被释放了
Now this Heat Monger's gonna go free because of me,
我感觉很愧疚
and I feel awful.
巴里  这并不是你的错
Barry, it's not your fault.
就只是  现在有一个恶人逍遥法外
It's just that now there's a bad guy on the streets,
而我却无能为力
and I can't do anything about it.
怎么了  我以前不会这么讲吗
What? Is that not something I would've said before?
这恰恰就是你以前会说的话
That is exactly something you would've said before.
你永远都是这样想要出力的
There's just something about you that always wants to help.
这是我们的家吗
This is our place?
我们怎么住的起这样的房子
How do we afford to live here?
你品位可真好
You have great taste.
实际上  这可都是你的功劳
Uh, actually, this is all you.
简直难以置信
I find that hard to believe.
-那是我吗  -是啊
- Is that me? - Yeah.
这两人是谁
Who are these people?
他们是你的父母
They're your parents.
你完全不记得发生了什么吗
You don't remember anything about what happened?
怎么了  发生了很糟的事情吗
Why, did something bad happen?
他们去世了
They died.
让人很意外  不过
It was unexpected, but...
他们去得很平静
they died peacefully.
所以你才搬来跟我和乔一起住
That's why you came to live with Joe and me.
我们是那时认识的吗
And that's when we met?
不是  我们在那之前就是朋友
Uh, no, actually, we were friends before then.
我记得我第一次见你的样子
I remember the first time that I saw you.
你是我见过最快乐的小男孩
You were the happiest boy that I'd ever met.
我感觉那是因为你走进了我的生活
I have a feeling that's because you entered my life.
没关系
It's okay.
怎么...
What the...
巴里  你没事吧
Barry! Are you okay?
我刚才怎么了
What just happened to me?!
这种超能力太酷了
These powers are so cool.
我能感觉到电流穿过我的身体
I can literally feel electricity coursing through my body.
会一直这样吗
I mean, is it always like this?
太不可思议了
This is amazing.
我们被泼了冷水
We just walked into a buzzkill.
我的出现总能扫大家的兴
My presence usually dampens the mood.
-乔  不要开枪  -你开枪  我也会
- Joe, don't. - You fire, I'll fire.
她来这里干什么
What the hell is she doing here?
-她想来帮忙  -帮忙
- She wants to help. - Help?
帮什么忙
With what?
帮我们解决我失去了超能力的问题
With the fact that I lost my powers.
巴里  要不让我们和她谈谈
Barry, why don't you give us a minute?
当然可以  你是个超级大反派吗
Sure, yeah. Are you like a super villain?
随口问问  好吧
Just asking. Okay.
这是怎么回事
How did this happen?
你们消除了巴里的记忆
You got rid of Barry's memories.
巴里记得什么  萨维塔就记得什么
What Barry remembers, Savitar remembers.
所以萨维塔也失忆了吗
So Savitar's lost his memories too?
萨维塔失忆了  于是他没法
Savitar loses his memory, he doesn't go along
让沃利拥有超能力
with the plan to give Wally powers.
因果关系
Cause and effect.
但如果你们让我帮忙
But if you let me help you figure out
想办法让巴里恢复记忆
how to get Barry's memories back,
就能一切如初
everything goes back to the way it was.
闪电小子又有超级速度了
Kid Flash runs again.
萨维塔也幸免于难
And Savitar survives.
但爱瑞丝会死
And Iris dies.
生活中处处都是艰难的抉择
Life's full of difficult choices.
或不用抉择
Or it isn't.
如果萨维塔的记忆恢复了
If Savitar gets his memory back,
那你会怎么样
what's in it for you?
这是我的问题
That's my business.
你觉得那个巴里能成为闪电侠吗
You think that Barry can become The Flash?
是的  他可以学
Yeah. He can learn.
我还记得该怎么做
I still know how to do everything.
我能教他
I can teach him.
好吧
Okay.
也许你们可以这样打败萨维塔
Maybe this is how you defeat Savitar.
但这座城市中还有很多坏人
But there's still a lot of villains in this city,
却没有闪电侠来保护它
and no Flashes to protect it.
你们真的愿意冒这个风险吗
Is that really a chance you're willing to take?
-我还没走  -是的  你还在呢
- I'm still here. - Yeah, you are.
因为你走了  我就得留下来
Because when you left, I stayed.
我们得谈谈这个显而易见的事
We gotta talk about the elephant in the room.
但你知道吗  我...
But you know what, I--
我有工作要做
I have a job to do.
我们得造出那个装置
We have to build that device.
我们必须得专注于手头的任务
We've got to focus on the task at hand.
你明白我的意思吗
Do you understand what I'm saying?
-完全明白  -从现在起
- I totally understand. - From here on out,
不管我什么时候注视着你那
whenever I look into your azure eyes,
湛蓝中带点灰色的双眼
flecked with gray,
就像夏天的暴雨即将
like a summer rainstorm coming to
轻吻着我的嘴
kiss my lips,
我只会思考一件事
the only thing I'm gonna be thinking about
就是如何最大程度地激励
is how I can best inspire that
那聪慧性感的大脑
beautiful, sexy brain.
火花
Sparks.
你也感觉到了
You felt them too.
-没有  -没有吗
- No. - No?
不  我是说是的  很明显
No, I mean yes, obviously.
-是的  -火花
- Oh, yeah. - Sparks.
在两条平行导线之间跳动
Jumping between two parallel wires--
一个改造的高电压爬弧
a modified high-voltage climbing arc.
我想我已经完成我的工作了
I guess my work here is done.
没有凯特琳你不该尝试这个
You should never have tried this without Caitlin.
好吧  我们现在也别无他选了  不是吗
Well, we didn't really have much of choice, now, did we?
而且  你不要对自己用第三人称
Also, don't refer to yourself in the third person.
凯特琳就是你  你们是同一人
It's Caitlin. It's you. It's the same person.
只是会混乱
It's just confusing.
把吉拉德处理器给我
Hand me the girard processor.
这能帮他打开新皮层和内侧额叶
It'll help prime his neocortical and medial frontal lobes.
怎么了
What?
没什么
Nothing.
天啊  看看我们
Oh, golly. Look at us.
三剑客努力不懈地干活
Just three musketeers working away.
就像之前一样
Just like old times, huh?
朱利安  凯特琳有跟你说过
Hey, Julian, did Caitlin ever tell you about our time
我们跟罗尼研究粒子加速器的时光吗
working on the Particle Accelerator with Ronnie?
没有  她没说过
No. No, she did not.
曾经有一次
There was this one time
我们有个很严格的期限
we had this very strict deadline,
威尔斯博士对我们超严厉
and Dr. Wells was super hard on us.
我们所有人  包括哈特利
All of us, even Hartley.
谁是哈特利
Who's--who's Hartley?
他是曾经和我们共事的人
Oh, he was this guy we used to work with.
是个混蛋  你刚加入时
Such a dick. You actually reminded me a lot of him
勾起了我对他的许多回忆
when you first came onboard.
总之  我们在研究铱电镀
Anyway, so we were working on the iridium plating
以用来...
for the...
那个叫什么来着
What was it called again?
同步加速器  就是那个
The synchrotron, that's what it was.
总之  我们很努力
So anyway, we were struggling,
我们一起熬通宵
and we were burning the midnight oil,
但我们无法让𬭊电容器
and we could not get the dubnium capacitor
储存任何电荷
to hold a single charge.
然后突然间
And so all of a sudden
罗尼失控了
Ronnie just loses all his chill.
他满脸通红
He turns beet red
他对着装置大吼
and he starts yelling at the thing like,
"搞什么  你个蠢呆的电容器"
"Come on, you dumb-nium capacitor!"
"储存电容"
"Take charge."
是的
Yes!
Yes.
天啊
Oh, my God.
我最珍惜的那些记忆
I think about all the memories I cherish most, and...
都有你的参与  凯特琳
and you're in every single one of them, Caitlin.
快做完它吧
Let's figure this out.
我不想在这多待一秒
I don't want to be here any longer than I have to.
你随意
Suit yourself.
好吧
Okay!
各位  我还是无法相信我有这些超能力
Guys, I still can't believe I have these powers.
它们太棒了
They're amazing.
我是说
I mean...
我觉得我可以当超级英雄
I think that I could be a superhero.
好吧  我可以再去跑一跑吗
All right, well is it cool if I run some more?
-去吧  -好吧
- Have at it. - All right.
我很久没看见他这么开心了
I haven't seen him this happy in a long time.
不曾有过
Try ever.
这是他第一次
It's the first time he hasn't been weighed down
没有背负过去的悲剧  知道吗
by the tragedies of his past, you know?
他第一次真正被释放出来
First time he's actually been free of them.
你不想他找回记忆  是吗
You don't want his memory restored, do you?
爸爸  我...
Dad, I...
我不得不说看着他开心和轻松
I can't say that seeing him happy and light
是我对他的愿望
isn't something I have wished for him,
因为确实是这样
because yeah, it is.
宝贝  这也是我对他的愿望
Sweetheart, I wish that for him, too.
但你爱上的不是闪电侠
But you didn't fall in love with The Flash.
你爱上的是巴里·艾伦
You fell in love with Barry Allen.
爸爸  我知道这不是原来的他
Dad, I know this is a different version of him,
但他...
but he's...
他还是巴里
he's still Barry.
不  他不是  宝贝
No, he's not, honey.
直到昨天
Look, until yesterday,
巴里所生活的28年里所有经历
Barry had 28 years of experiences
造就了他  其中有些记忆是不好的
to define him, and some of those memories were bad,
但有些却是好的
but some were good, too.
但没了那些记忆
But without those memories,
我们认识和爱的巴里·艾伦就不存在了
the Barry Allen we know and love is gone.
我不知道  爸爸
I don't know, Dad.
我有时不禁认为
You know, part of me can't help but
这是份礼物  你知道
think that this is some sort of gift, you know--that
这是他本该有的生活
this is the life that he was supposed to have.
也许这座城市不需要闪电侠
Maybe the city doesn't need The Flash.
大家好
Hey, everybody!
周五快乐
Happy Friday!
所以我是个超级英雄
So I am a superhero?
是的  货真价实
Yeah. A real good one.
你是闪电侠
You're The Flash.
你确定红衣侠不会更好听吗
You sure The Streak isn't a better name, maybe?
打开电视
Turn on the TV.
好吧
Uh, okay. Yeah.
目击者说对大楼放火的人
Eyewitnesses say the man who set the fire
不是别人  正是卢西奥斯·库里奇
to the offices is none other than Lucious Coolidge,
也就是热侠
AKA Heat Monger.
他是因为我才获得自由的
That's the guy that went free because of me.
按这个速度  大楼
At this rate, it won't be long
很快就会被烧成平地
before the whole thing burns down.
有数百人在里面工作
There's hundreds of people who work in there.
我们得出手阻止
We need to stop it.
怎么阻止  你现在不能
How? I mean, you can't right now.
不  但我能
No, but I can.
巴里  你不知道怎么用你的能力
Barry, you don't know how to use your powers.
-巴仔  -你刚说我是超级英雄
- Bar-- - You just said I'm a superhero.
而且货真价实  对吗
And a good one, right?
不管有没有记忆  我不能袖手旁观
I mean, memories or not, I can't stand by
看人们被烧死  而不去阻止
and watch people die if I can prevent it.
忘了穿战衣
Forgot the suit.
巴里  你还好吗
Barry? You okay?
是的  我还好
Uh, yeah, I'm good.
很难停下
Stopping's hard.
我怎么救里面的人
How do I save everybody inside?
你就把他们带出来
You just run them out of there.
我自己很难才来到这
I barely got here myself.
我要怎么把其他人带出来
How am I supposed to run with someone else?
我们一定能做点什么
There's gotta be something we can do.
我们能做一件事
There is something we can do:
用那个装置帮他打开大脑
jump-start his brain using that thing.
我们还没做测试
We have not done a test run.
现在没有时间做测试了
There's no time to test it now.
那是什么装置
What is that thing?
这可以通过他战衣的传送器
This can send electrical charges through
发送电荷  理论上
the transmitters in his suit and theoretically,
应该能刺激他的记忆
should jolt his memory.
你要电击他的大脑
You want to electroshock his brain?
如果电击过度了呢
Won't that fry it even more?
如果我们不那么做
If we don't do that,
那里所有人都会死
all those people are gonna die.
生命就是碰运气的游戏
Life's a game of chance.
好吧  巴里  你会产生感觉
Okay, Barry, you're gonna feel something.
可能是痛苦  刺痛  或糟糕
Might hurt, might sting, might suck.
-等一下  你说什么  -可能三个都有
- Wait, what? - Probably all three.
好吧  我们开始了
Okay, here we go.
缩小突触活动
巴里
Barry?
好吧  我还是不记得
Uh, yeah, I still don't remember.
为什么不成功
Why didn't that work?
本来应该成功的
That was supposed to work.
我们帮他打开了他的颞叶
We kick-started his temporal lobe.
现在他需要访问它
Now he just needs to access it.
就像汽油已经在油箱里  只需要点燃就行
Gas is in the tank, we just need to turn the ignition.
我们需要内心深刻的记忆激发他的大脑
We need a visceral memory to spark his brain.
好吧
Okay...
Okay.
巴里
Barry?
我需要你记起来
I need you to remember.
我做不到
I can't!
不不  你能做到
Yes, yes, you can.
好吗  好吧  听我说
Okay? Okay, listen to me.
你妈死的那晚
The night that your mom died,
我不想告诉你她怎么死的
I didn't want to tell you how,
但她死得不安详
but she didn't die peacefully.
她是被杀死的
She was murdered.
什么
What?
然后你搬来跟我们住
And you came to live with us.
我爸把你带进屋里
My dad brought you inside,
你还在震惊中  你没有哭泣
and you were in shock. You weren't crying.
那晚之后
And later that night,
我被一个声音吵醒  我从床上爬起来
a sound woke me, and I crawled out of my bed,
我发现声音是从楼下传上来的
and I realized that the sound was coming from downstairs.
我从楼梯的扶栏窥看
I peered over the banister, and...
我发现你一个人在哭
I found you crying alone.
我知道我得过去找你
I knew I had to go to you.
我坐在你旁边  让你的头
I sat next to you, and you put your head
靠在我膝盖上  抱着哭泣的你
in my lap, and I held you while you cried.
我那时不知道  但现在回想
And I didn't know it then, but now looking back,
我发现我们的爱是从那晚开始的
I realize that that was the night that we fell in love.
我们在那晚发现
That was the night that we realized
我们有多需要对方
how much we needed each other.
听着...
And look...
我非常希望我能带走你的黑暗记忆
I so wish that I could take your dark memories away.
我希望我能抹去所有的痛苦
I wish that I could make all of that pain go away,
但我不能
but I can't.
好吗  但我知道  我知道的是
Okay? But what I do know, what I know,
每个不好的记忆
is that for every bad memory,
都会有个好记忆带你挺过去
there is a good one to get you through it.
快跑  巴里  快跑
Run, Barry, run!
巴里
Barry?
我记得...
I remember...
我记得
I remember.
我记得一切了
I remember everything.
I remember everything!
现在这场火
Now for this fire.
我觉得我无法一个人灭掉它
I don't think I can put this fire out alone.
你不必一个人做
You don't have to.
棒
Yes!
看来你记得如何拯救危难了
Looks like you remembered how to save the day.
学过就忘不了
Like riding a bike.
-你妈妈的婚前姓  -汤普森
- Your mother's maiden name. - Thompson.
CODIS是什么的缩写
CODIS is an acronym for what?
DNA联合检索系统
Combined DNA Index System.
好吧  三年级时
Okay. In the third grade,
你给班上的仓鼠取名...
you renamed the class hamster to...
亚历山大·汉·贝尔
Alexander Ham Bell.
那时我八岁
I was eight years old.
所以你找回记忆了
So you got your memories back.
现在我们可以专注在阻止萨维塔了
Now we can all focus our attention on stopping Savitar.
祝好运
Good luck with that.
我们不会就这么让她走吧
Please tell me we're not gonna just let her walk out of here.
你们想打一场吗
Now you want to fight?
我们不想跟你打
We don't want to fight you.
这件事不可避免  不是吗
Can't really avoid that now, can we?
可以的  你可以留下来
Yeah, we can. You can stay here with us.
我们是你的朋友  你的家人
We're your friends. Your family.
凯特琳  我可以治好你
Caitlin, I can fix you.
你已经努力过了
You already tried.
那么我会更努力
Well then, I'll try harder.
我不管要付出什么代价
I don't care what it takes.
我不管我要怎么做
I don't care what I have to do.
我向你发誓  我会治好你
I swear to you, I will find you a cure.
凯特琳  我爱你
Caitlin, I love you.
我不爱你  朱利安
I don't love you, Julian.
我从来都没有
I never did.
你们任何人我都没爱过
I never loved any of you.
她走了吗
She's gone?
是的
Yeah.
也许已经不可挽回了
Maybe too far gone now.
我们会想到办法把她找回来的
We'll figure out a way to get her back.
就像我们想到办法把你找回来一样
Just like we figured out how to get you back.
你确定你要的是这个我吗
You sure this is the me you want?
还有我带着的担子
With all the baggage?
看见你不用背负发生的一切
Seeing you without the weight of everything that's happened,
看见你像母亲被杀前那样开心
seeing you happy, like you were before your mother was killed?
所有的黑暗不再缠着你
Without all of that darkness haunting you,
你终于释放了
you were finally free.
感觉挺好的
It was nice.
几个月前我做过一样的事
I did the same thing months ago.
你说什么
What do you mean?
那种自由  我有过
That freedom? I had that.
我跟父母在闪点重聚的时候
When I was with my mom and dad again in Flashpoint,
我可以让它继续下去
and I could've let it stay like that.
我可以让这条时间线的记忆消退
I could've let the memories of this timeline fade,
但如果我那么做  我就会失去乔
but if I'd done that, I would've lost Joe,
西斯科  沃利  凯特琳  还有你
and Cisco, and Wally, and Caitlin, and you.
痛苦和黑暗  是我的一部分
Pain and darkness- it's a part of me.
是我的推动力
You know, I need it to fuel me,
让我成为更好的人
to push me to be a better person,
更好的英雄
to be a better hero.
让我永远都不会忘了我是谁
To keep me from ever forgetting who I am.
这个才是我认识和爱的巴里·艾伦
Now that is the Barry Allen I know and love.
你们...  好吧
Hey, you guys-- okay!
你们得过来看看这个
You guys, you got to come see this.
Y-you got to come see this.
那是什么
What is that?
这是神速力火箭筒
This is the Speed Force Bazooka.
很好  对吧
Good, right?
它可以困住萨维塔吗
And that's gonna trap Savitar?
有个小问题
There is a tiny little problem.
-什么问题  -就是...
- What's that? - It's...
为了产生足够的能量
In order to generate enough power
吸住萨维塔的辐向场
to magnetize Savitar's radial field
让他处于永久静止的状态
and keep him in a state of perpetual stasis--
-静止  -在神速力里面
- Stasis. - Inside the Speed Force,
我们需要我的计算
we need by my calculations--
-通过计算  -需要3.86兆焦耳的能量
- By calculations-- - 3.86 terajoules of energy.
我想这不止是
I'm guessing that's more energy
一节7号电池的能量
than a triple-A battery.
是的  这超过了一个太阳的能量
Yes. That's more energy than a sun.
我们要怎么
Where we gonna
才能找到这么大的能量呢
find something like that?